<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cleanup on AWS Serverless Catalog Workshop</title>
    <link>/en/070_cleanup/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cleanup on AWS Serverless Catalog Workshop</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/en/070_cleanup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Remove the Environment Stacks</title>
      <link>/en/070_cleanup/stacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/070_cleanup/stacks/</guid>
      <description>Delete the stacks for each environment created for our application aws cloudformation delete-stack --stack-name demo-service-Dev aws cloudformation delete-stack --stack-name demo-service-Staging aws cloudformation delete-stack --stack-name demo-service-Prod Make sure to refresh until your stacks are deleted to move forward </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delete the S3 Bucket</title>
      <link>/en/070_cleanup/s3bucket/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/070_cleanup/s3bucket/</guid>
      <description>Empty the S3 Bucket aws s3 rm s3://serverless-wksp-sample-&amp;lt;your-name&amp;gt; --recursive Delete the S3 Bucket aws s3 rb s3://serverless-wksp-sample-&amp;lt;your-name&amp;gt; --force </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Undeploy the Service Catalog</title>
      <link>/en/070_cleanup/service-catalog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/070_cleanup/service-catalog/</guid>
      <description>Let us now terminate the provisioned product in Service Catalog as well as deleting both the product and portifolio we created.
Empty the Build Artifact S3 Bucket Go to your AWS CloudFormation and search for the stack Service Catalog created starting with the SC- prefix. Go to Outputs and take note of the ArtifactBucket S3 Bucket name. aws s3 rm s3://&amp;lt;YOUR-ARTIFACT-BUCKET-NAME&amp;gt; --recursive Terminate provisioned product aws servicecatalog terminate-provisioned-product --provisioned-product-name demo-service Go to your Service Catalog console in Provisioned Products and wait until the termination is complete to move forward Remove product association from the portifolio  Go to Portifolios.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delete the CodeCommit Repositories</title>
      <link>/en/070_cleanup/commit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/070_cleanup/commit/</guid>
      <description>aws codecommit delete-repository --repository-name demo-service-repo </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cleanup the Workspace</title>
      <link>/en/070_cleanup/workspace/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/070_cleanup/workspace/</guid>
      <description>Since we no longer need the Cloud9 instance to have Administrator access to our account, we can delete the workspace we created:
 Go to your Cloud9 Environment. Select the environment named serverless-catalog-workshop and pick delete.  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>